what did I really lose that day?
ano hi honto ni ushinatta monotte nan dattakke
for the life of me I can't remember
tou ni wasureteshimatta yo
we slowly lost sight of each other in the twilight
yuugure de futari sukoshizutsu mienakunatteitte
and yet we're stuck here unable to go home
sore nanoni bokura kaerezu ni ita
weak, frail souls lost in the world
dokoka ni kowaresou na moroi kokoro
we act strong to hide their fragility
tsuyogaru kotoba de ootte kakushiteru
九尾の力か。
hide their fragility
ootte kakushiteru
so farewell, but even forced apart
sayonara aenakunattatte
怒りで ナルトと
呼応するようだな。
our stories go on
bokura wa tsuzuki ga aru kara
even in a world without you, I run
kimi no inai sekai datte hashiru yo
to someday get past the pain
itsuka no itami mo koete
はっ！
Planetary Devastation
The power of the Nine-Tails...
はっ！
It's responding to Naruto's rage.
俺が憎いか？
Do you hate me?
これでも 人は本当の意味で
理解しあえると言えるか？
Do you still think people can
truly understand one another?
それでいい。
Your actions are justified.
だがな…。
But know this...
俺の痛みは お前以上だ！
My pain is far greater than yours!
いくぞ！
Let's go!
フンッ この程度か。
Is that all you've got?
やるな。
Not bad.
(サクラ)このチャクラの感じ。
This chakra...
あのときの…。
I've felt it before.
どうなってるの？
What's going on?
ヒナタ様が
ナルトを助けようと出ていかれて。
Hinata-sama went out to
save Naruto.
まさか…。
Don't tell me she's...
《封印術か》
A Sealing Jutsu?
《封印を解いた》
He broke the Seal...
《くる！》
Here he comes!
《速い！》
He's fast!
神羅天征！
Almighty Push!
《バカな 神羅天征に耐えるだと!?》
Impossible...
He withstood my Almighty Push!
(ヒナタ)ナルト君。
Naruto-kun.
万象天引！
Universal Pull!
なにっ？
What was that?!
ああっ！
すごい… なんだ あれは？
Oh my god... What is that?
ナルトは どうなってますか？
Is something happening with Naruto?
なんて言ったらいいか…。
I'm not exactly sure what to make of it.
とにかく ナルトから６本のシッポが！
That aside, Naruto's showing six-tails!
このままだと
もしかしたら九尾に。
At this rate, he may end up
transforming into the Nine-Tails.
《６本… ６本って
じゃあ あのときより 更に！
Six tails?!
Six... It's much worse
than last time!
カツユ様 すぐに避難するように
みんなに伝えてください。
Katsuyu-sama. Please tell everyone
to evacuate immediately.
(いの)今度は何!?
Now what?
ぶっちゃけ もう木ノ葉の
原形がなくなっちゃってます！
The Leaf Village is destroyed
beyond recognition.
(カツユ)急いで ここから なるべく
遠くへ避難してください！
You must all evacuate
as far away as you can!
これは ナルト君の九尾の力です。
This is due to Naruto-kun's
Nine-Tails power!
私の分身が ナルト君に
くっついているので わかります。
I know because my clone is
attached to Naruto-kun.
(シカマル)九尾化か。
He transformed into the Nine-Tails?
ヤマトとカカシで 封印術を
ナルトに施していたはずだぞ。
But Yamato and Kakashi should have
placed a Sealing Jutsu on him!
いったい どういうことだ!?
How did this happen?
ヒナタさんです。 ヒナタさんが
ナルト君をかばって➡
It was Hinata-san.
She tried to save Naruto-kun and
was taken down right in front of him.
目の前で倒されました。
それで ナルト君が…。
And then Naruto-kun...
それが引き金か。
はい おそらく。
So that triggered his transformation?
Yes... probably.
ヤマトは どうなった？
こんなときに どこにいるんだ？
Where is Yamato?
What is he doing at a time like this?
(アンコ)カブトは いたか？
Did you find Kabuto?
(サイ)いました。
(アンコ)よし 気取られるなよ。
Yes.
Good. Don't let him spot you.
(ヤマト)うっ… こ これは!?
Wh-What?!
どうした？
What is it?
まさか あの封印術を自力で。
"Six"
It can't be... He undid
the Sealing Jutsu on his own!
６本なんて ありえないぞ！
Six Tails?! That's insane!
緊急事態だ。
There's an emergency.
すまないが 僕は今すぐ里に帰る。
Sorry, but I must return to the village!
おい！
H-Hey!
九尾の力 すばらしいものだな。
The power of the Nine-Tails...
How magnificent.
フッ！
ナルトもペインも
里から どんどん離れていくぞ。
Both Naruto and Pain are
moving away from the village.
どういうこと？
What?
九尾化したナルトに押され
ペインが逃げ出したようだ。
It seems Pain is fleeing
from the Nine-Tails Naruto.
ざまあねえの。 ウハハッ！
Serves him right!
笑ってる場合じゃない。
This is no time for laughs.
今のうちに
ヒナタの身柄を確保して➡
We have to make sure Hinata is okay,
それと
今のナルトをどうにかしないと…。
and then do something
about Naruto.
ああなったナルトは
見境なく人を襲うはず。
The way he is now,
he'll attack anyone in sight.
《とにかく ヤマト隊長と
連絡を取らなきゃ》
I have to get a hold
of Captain Yamato.
(長門)天道を十分 近づけた。
I've brought Tendo close enough.
地爆天星。
Planetary Devastation...
(小南)そこまでしなくても。
もう あなたの体が…。
You don't have to go that far.
Your body can't take any more.
少し黙ってろ 小南
集中する。
Silence, Konan. I must focus.
地爆天星！
Planetary Devastation!
ハァーッ！
むぅ～！
うお～！
何も ここまで大きなものを。
Why did you push yourself
to make it that huge?
相手は九尾だ
手は抜けない。
My opponent is the Nine-Tails.
I cannot ease up.
それに
六道仙人のつくったといわれる➡
The Sage of the Six Paths is
said to have created the moon.
月に比べれば
たいしたことはない。
This is nothing compared to that.
とにかく これで九尾捕獲完了だ。
Regardless...
I have now captured the Nine-Tails.
《なんでだ
なんで こうなっちまう？》
Why?
Why did it come to this?
((お前なら 平和をつくるために
この憎しみと どう向き合う？
How would you confront this hatred,
in order to create peace?
(お前の答えを聞こう))
I want to hear your answer.
《そんなの わからねえ。
How should I know?
苦しい イヤだ》
It hurts... I hate this.
わからねえ 俺ってば
どうすりゃいい？
I don't know...
What am I supposed to do?
もう 何もわからねえ！
I don't know anything anymore!
誰か 助けてくれ！
Someone, help me...
答えを 教えてくれ。
Give me the answer.
(九尾)すべてを壊せ。
Destroy everything.
苦しむもの すべてをなくせ。
Erase everything that hurts.
お前の心を すべて ワシに預けろ。
Give me your soul.
そうすれば 苦しみから
お前を救ってやる。
I will save you from your suffering.
うわ！
(九尾)そうだ それでいい。
Yes... You're doing fine.
"Eight"
《八だって!? やばい
本当にやばいよ これは》
Eight?! This is bad.
This is really, really bad!
ここまでとはな。
I never imagined it would
be this powerful.
こっちに来い。
Come over here.
さあ この封印の札を
引きちぎってくれ。
Come...
Rip this Seal off me.
《あっ クソ！ もうダメだ。
Dammit... It's too late.
どうして こんな…》
"Nine"
How could this happen?
"Fourth Hokage"
お前は！
You're...
四代目火影。
Fourth... Hokage...
(ミナト)ナルト。
Naruto...
when the fireworks suddenly explode in the air
fui ni agatta hanabi wo futari de miageta toki
I couldn't keep my eyes off from your face
muchuu de miteru kimi no kao wo
I gazed at you quietly
sotto nusumimita no
it'd be so much easier if I was able to hate you
kimi no koto kirai ni naretara ii noni
because I always remember you in situations like this
kyou mitai na hi ni wa kitto
I can't help but think about the times we spent together
mata omoidashiteshimau yo
I'm ready to forget you
mou wasureyou kimi no koto zenbu
it just tears at my heart too much
konna ni mo kanashikute
I wonder why did we meet each other
doushite deatteshimattan darou
when I close my eyes
me wo tojireba
It's like you are here
ima mo kimi ga soko ni iru you de
Next Episode
Why did you seal the Nine-Tails inside of me?!
(ミッシェル)どうして泣いてるの？
(ルーシィ)だって みんな
いなくなっちゃうんだもん。
I had to go through so much because of it!
I trained really hard, met a lot of people,
ママもパパも 大事にしてた妹も。
and it made me really happy!
But then the Akatsuki came after me, and my friends!
思い出してくれたの？
うん。
Dammit, I don't know what I'm saying anymore!
ごめんね 私…。
It must have been hard for you...
謝らないで。
I'm sorry, Naruto.
思い出してくれただけでも
嬉しいもの。
Next time on Naruto Shippuden: "Fourth Hokage"
Fourth Hokage
ミッシェル…。
How old are you now, Naruto?